乔伊  这就是你爸妈叫你不要跳上床的原因
See, Joe,that's why your parents told you not to jump on the bed!
看看我  我在做果酱
Hey,look at me! I'm making jam!
我早上四点就起来了
Been at it since 4 this morning.
那么早你从哪儿买的水果
Where'd you get fruit 4 in the morning?
在码头那儿买的
Went down to the docks.
你一定不知道那里可以买到批发价
Bet ya didn't know you could get it wholesale.
我根本不知道码头在哪
I didn't know there were docks.
手臂断了吗
Is it broken?
不  但得挂着这玩意 几个星期
No, but I gotta wear this thing for a couple weeks.
你有没有告诉医生  你是因为跳上床才受伤
Did You tell the doctor you did it jumping up and down on your bed?
不  我编的故事
No. I had a whole story
本来可以蒙混过去的  但是...
worked out,but then...
钱德勒出卖了我
...Chandler sold me out.
抱歉  我想医生不会相信
Well, I'm sorry Joe. I didn't think the doctor
你的胳膊是"自己脱臼的"
was gonna buy that it just "fell out of the socket."
这是什么  水果吗
What is this? Fruit?
莫妮卡在做果酱
Monica's making jam.
我最爱果酱了  我们家怎么从来没有果酱
Jam? I love jam! How come we never have jam at our place?
因为咱得攒钱给孩子们买新鞋
Because the kids need new shoes.
我得做正事了  各位
I'm going into business, people.
我不想再为理查的事伤神
I'm sick of being depressed about Richard.
我需要一个计划  来忘记我的男人
I needed a plan. A plan to get over my man.
跟想男人恰恰相反的事是什么  做果酱
What's the opposite of man? Jam!
乔伊  别吃  太烫了
Joey,don't! It's way too hot!
这一桶就算我的好了
This'll just be my batch.
到此为止  够了
That's it. No.
这位穿杰克鲁牌的家伙
Hey,you, J. Crew guy....
你干嘛跟踪我
Why have you been following me?
这一周来  我走到哪儿都能看见你
I mean, all week long,everywhere I look,there's you.
你也不回电话  又把我的信退回来
You wouldn't return my calls. You sent back my letters.
什么
What?
再给我一次机会  厄休拉  拜托
One more chance, Ursula. Please.
真是太尴尬了
Oh, oh, oh, this is awkward.
因为你要找的是厄休拉
Yeah, because you want Ursula,
我是菲比  我们是双胞胎
and I'm Phoebe. Twin sisters.
我说真的
Seriously.
太好了  我跟错人了
That's great. I'm stalking the wrong woman.
我真是个糊涂蛋
I am such a dingus!
你不是糊涂蛋
Oh, you're not a dingus.
我只想让你知道  我以前不是这样的
I just, I want you to know I didn't used to be like this.
在认识你姐姐之前
Before I met your sister,
我只是个贩卖寻呼机和手机的普通人
I was like this normal guy who sold beepers and cellular phones.
这不是你的错
Look,it's not your fault. You know I mean...
她就是这么对待男人的
this is just what she does to guys,okay?
谢谢你
Well,thanks.
等等  我有个小故事告诉你
Wait. You know what, I got a little story.
我上初中的时候  有一段时间
When I was in Junior high school, I went through a period
总以为自己是女巫
where I thought I was a witch.
那时有个辅导老师对我说的话
And there was this guidance counselor who said something to me
我想可以帮助你
that I think will help you a lot.
他说  "你根本不是女巫
He said,"Okay,you're not a witch.
你只是个普通学生"
You're just an average student."
-你听懂我的意思了吗  -不太懂
-See what I'm saying? -Not really.
忘了她吧
Well,get over it.
你看起来是个不错的人
I mean you, you just seem to be a really nice guy, you know.
别对自己太苛刻  好吗
Don't be so hard on yourself,okay?
没错  你说得对  谢谢你对我这么友善
You're right. I know you're right. And thanks for being so nice.
给
Here.
谢谢你
Thanks a lot.
你要不要去喝杯咖啡
Do you want to get a cup of coffee?
-好啊  -走吧
-Yeah, okay. - Okay.
你不用再跟在我后面了
You don't have to walk behind me anymore.
-莫妮卡  -莫妮卡
- Mon?  - Mon?
"去买罐子  等会儿回来
"Gone for more jars. Back later.
莫妮卡·盖勒"
Monica Geller."
等等  你看
Wait a minute. Look!
-快看快看  -什么什么
- Look, look, look!  - What, what, what?
整个房子里都没人
It's an empty apartment.
这间空房子里  只有我们两个
We're all alone in an empty apartment.
宝贝  拜托
Honey, come on.
我在十分钟内得出发去上班
I have to be at work like in 10 minutes.
好吧  我又不是什么年度模范员工
All right. Alright, it's not like I'm employee of the year or anything.
在这里啊
There it is!
这就是你要找的啊
Oh,that's what you are talking about.
我看起来很胖吗
Do I look fat?
-不胖  -不胖
- No. - No.
这么说我完全可以接受
Okay, I accept that.
当珍妮斯问我时  我也说了不
When Janice asked me and I said no,
她却理解为  我觉得她像只母牛
she took that as I was calling her a cow.
好吧  情景重现一下  重现一下
Okay, walk us through it,honey. Walk us through it.
珍妮斯问  "我今天看起来胖吗"
Okay, well, Janice said,"Hi. Do I look fat today?"
于是我就看了看她
And I looked at her...
等等  你看了看她
Wow, wow, wow, you looked at her?
你决不能迟疑
You never look.
你只能直接回答  就像条件反射一样
You just answer. It's like a reflex.
"我看起来胖吗"  "不"
"Do I look fat?" "No."
"她比我漂亮吗"  "不"
"Is she prettier than I am?" "No."
"尺寸很重要吗"  "不"
"Does size matter?" "No."
这一条男女都适用
And it works both ways.
这些你们天生就知道吗
So you both just know this stuff?
吵了大概三四十次后  你大概就领悟了
You know, after about 30 or 40 fights,you kind of catch on.
是啊  例如
Okay. For instance:
假如珍妮斯旅行回来
Let's say, Janice is coming back from a trip.
她给你两种选择
She gives you two options.
选择一  她从机场自己打车回来
Option one: She'll take a cab home from the airport.
选择二  你在领行李的地方与她碰面
Or Option two: You can meet her at baggage claim.
你会怎么做
What do you do?
简单  领行李的地方
That's easy. Baggage claim.
错  这下你就变单身了
And wrong! Now you're single.
其实是第三个秘密绝招
It's actually secret option number three.
你要在出舱口等她  这样她才知道你爱她
You meet her at the gate. That way she knows you love her.
好  这么说有道理  有道理
Okay,this is good. This is good.
好  我还有一个问题
All right, I have one.
珍妮斯晚上喜欢拥抱
Janice likes to cuddle...
我当然也喜欢拥抱
at night, which I'm all for.
不过到睡觉的时候
But you know, when you want to go to sleep,
你会想要一点自己的空间
you want some space.
我要怎样告诉她才不至于...
So how do I tell her that without...
让诸如不小心说她胖之类的意外发生
...you know,accidentally calling her fat or something?
抱歉  这我们帮不了你
Oh, honey. I'm sorry we can't help you there,
因为我们都是抱着睡的
because we're cuddly sleepers.
好了  我上班要迟到了
Okay, I'm late for work.
-你们要不要下来  -好  等一下就去
- Are you guys gonna come down? - Yeah, yeah. I, I'm right behind you.
祝你好运  钱德勒
Okay, Good luck, Chandler.
谢谢你  瑞秋  拜
Thank you, Rachel. Bye.
-回见  甜心  -拜  宝贝
- Bye, sweetie. - Bye, hon.
好了  睡觉那个问题
Okay, the sleeping thing.
很不容易解决  但也不是没办法
Very tricky business, but there is something you can do.
我还以为你们都是"抱着睡的"
I thought you guys were "cuddly sleepers."
不是
No.
不  不是抱着睡的  不是我  只有她
No, not cuddly. Not me. Just her.
我跟你一样  需要空间
I'm like you. I need the room.
好  到这儿来
Okay, come here.
-好  假设你现在在床上  -好
- Okay. You're in bed. - Yeah.
-我还是用垫子好了  -好的
- I gonna use the cushion. - Yeah.
好了  假设你在床上
Okay. You're in bed.
她在你旁边  抱着你
She's over on your side,cuddling.
现在  你等她逐渐睡着
Now,you wait for her to drift off...
然后你抱住她...
...and then you hug her...
把她滚到床的另一边
...and roll her over to her side of the bed.
接着你...
And then you...
再滚到旁边去
... roll away.
拥抱是为了她
Hug for her.
滚走是为了自己
Roll for you.
-这就是经典的"拥抱与翻滚"  -没错
- Okay, the old "hug and roll." - Yeah.
-还有一个问题 -说吧
- One question. - Sure.
你刚才是把枕头当作女生  对吧
You're pretending the pillow's a girl,right?
记得小时候
Remember when you were a kid,
妈妈会把你送到电影院...
your mom would drop you off to the movies...
给你一罐果酱和一只小汤匙
...with a jar of jam and a little spoon?
你真可爱
You're so pretty.
-嗨  -嗨  菲比
-Hi.  -Hi, Phoebe.
你知道那个跟踪我的人吗
Hey, you know that guy who's been following me?
我今天跟他说话了
I talked to him today.
你跟他说话  你疯了吗
You talked to him? Are you crazy?
第一  我没有疯  第二  说话别乱喷
Okay, first,I'm not crazy. And second,say it, don't spray it.
总之他名叫麦尔科姆  他也不是在跟踪我
Anyway, his name is Malcolm, and he wasn't following me.
我是说  他在跟踪没错
I mean, he was,
但他要跟的是厄休拉
but just 'cause he thought I was Ursula.
所以他不敢上前来跟我说话
That's why he couldn't just come up and talk to me.
因为有限制令嘛
Because of the restraining order.
我还是对麦尔科姆没有好感
Not feeling better about Malcolm.
不  他不是疯子
No, no, he's not a kook.
他只是个非常热情  极度浪漫的家伙
He's just this very passionate, incredibly romantic guy...
只是表现得有点过火了而已
...that just got a teensy bit carried away, you know.
我们相处得很好  而且他很可爱
We just get along really well, and he's so cute.
天啊  你竟然暗恋跟踪你妹妹的人
Oh, my God! You've got a crush on your sister's stalker.
我要帮他忘记厄休拉的一切
No, just gonna help him, you know, get "de-Ursula-ized."
就像乔伊跟她分手后  我陪他疗伤一样
Like, you know, like I did for Joey after he went out with her.
可我没有跟踪她
I didn't stalk her, I mean.
这不是重点好么
I asked for the news, not the weather.
-嗨  大伙儿  -嗨  莫妮卡
-Hi, guys. - Hi, Mon.
乔伊  这是你的  黑莓红醋粟酱
Joey,this is for you. It's blackberry currant.
乔伊  我得问你
Okay, Joe, I got to ask.
影印店的那个女孩  全裸
The girl from the xerox place, buck naked...
一大缸果酱  你选哪个
...or a big tub of jam?
左右手通吃
Put your hands together.
乔伊  你慢慢享用吧  那是最后一瓶了
Joey, take your time with that. It's my last batch.
没有果酱了
No more jam?
你的果酱大计怎么不继续了
What happened to your jam plan?
我算过了  我每罐得卖17元才能收回成本
I figured out I'd need to charge $17 a jar just to break even.
所以我有了个新计划  生小孩
So I've got a new plan now. Babies.
那你可能需要更大的罐子了
Well,you're gonna need much bigger jars.
-你胡说什么呢  -我说我打算生孩子
- What are you talking about? - I'm talking about me having a baby.
-你说真的吗  -是啊
- What? Are you serious? - Yeah.
做果酱的好处在于
The great thing about the jam plan
它让我重新掌握自己的人生
was I was taking control of my life.
所以我扪心自问
So I ask myself,
这个世界上对我来说什么是最重要的呢
"What is the most important thing to me in the world?"
于是我就想到了生孩子
And that's when I came up with the baby plan.
你是不是忘了一点
Aren't you forgetting something?
那人叫什么来着  "爸爸"
What is that guy's name? Dad!
我花了28年  去找一个能托付终身的男人
It took me 28 years to find one man I wanted to spend my life with.
如果我还得再等28年
If I have to wait another 28 years,
那我生孩子就得56岁了
I'll be 56 before I can have a baby.
那样实在太愚蠢了
And that's just stupid.
那才是愚蠢的点吗
That's what's stupid?
我并不需要一个真正的男人
I don't need an actual man.
我只要他几颗会游泳的小种子
Just a couple of his best swimmers.
而且那些东西  也是有地方能买到的
And there are places you can go to get that...stuff.
又要去码头了吗
Down to the docks again?
晚安  宾宝贝
Night-night,Bing-a-ling.
晚安
Night-night...
珍妮斯
...Janice.
看看她那边的位置
Look at all the room on her side!
都够放一只大企鹅了
You could fit a giant penguin over there.
不过那样会很奇怪
That'd be weird,though.
要开始"拥抱与翻滚"了
Okay, hug and roll time.
先是拥抱  抱住她
I'm hugging. I'm hugging.
翻滚起来  接着...
You're rolling,and....
太好了  你自由了
Yes! Freedom!
除了这只手臂
Except for this arm!
我被卡住了  手臂卡住了
I'm stuck. Stuck arm.
好了  我们玩过去那种掀桌布游戏
Okay, time for the old tablecloth trick.
只需一个流畅的动作
One fluid motion.
像猫一样矫捷  像猫一样矫捷
Quick like a cat. Quick like a cat.
一  二
And one,two...
三
... three!
这是我的双眼望远镜
Here's my binoculars.
很好  你做得很好  非常坚强
Oh,great. You're doing great. You know, really strong.
很不错  保持保持
Going strong. Keep going.
这是我的夜视镜
These are my night-vision goggles.
这是我在公园里看她时  假装阅读的书
This is the book I pretend to read when I'm watching her in the park.
这些是接字游戏  只是为了解闷
And these are Madlibs. They're just for fun.
当然
Oh, yeah.
这是什么
What's this?
这是我写的日志  记录她的一举一动
This is the log I kept,recording her every movement.
你要不要听听看
Do you want to hear some from it?
我一点也不想听
Not even a little bit.
是跟你有关的
It's about you.
那好吧
Oh, okay then.
"我今天遇到菲比
"l met Phoebe today.
她对我很好  即使我是就是个大屌丝
She was really nice to me even though I'm such a loser.
我走在回家路上  一直想着她
And when I was walking home,I thought about her a lot.
虽然很奇怪  但感觉很棒"
It was weird, but kind of cool."
很好
Good.
当时你在想什么
So what were you thinking?
我在想  亲你是什么感觉
I was thinking what it'd be like to kiss you.
真的
Really?
不
No.
我是故意这么说的
See, that's just something I said now
这样我才有可能亲到你
so that maybe I could kiss you.
好吧
Oh, okay.
不  不用了我刚吃了一罐芥末
No,it's all right. I just had a jar of mustard.
好  捐精者编号03815的资料来了
Okay. Sperm donor number 03815,come on down!
他身高一米八  体重77公斤
Okay, he's 6'2", 170 pounds.
形容自己是男版吉娜·戴维斯[选美小姐]
He describes himself as a male Gina Davis.
你是想说还有别人像我们这么优秀
You mean there's more than one of us?
你不能这样做  莫妮卡
You can't do this,Mon.
如果你这么做  我会  我会
If you do this,I'm gonna, I'm gonna...
-你会怎样  -我会告诉我妈
- You're gonna what? - I'm gonna tell Mom.
抱歉  他说得对  我爱你
I'm sorry,but he's right. I love you,
可是你真的疯了
but you're crazy.
-没错  -什么  这有什么疯狂的
- Crazy. - What? Why? Why is this crazy?
就算这不是生孩子的理想途径
So this isn't the ideal way to do something...
这不是理想途径...
Oh,it's not the ideal way...
嘴唇动着呢  我还在讲话
Lips moving. Still talking.
这样可能不太理想  但...
It may not be ideal,but...
我真的准备好了
... I'm so ready.
我看到本看着你的样子
I see the way Ben looks at you.
刺痛了我  你知道吗
It makes me ache,you know?
瞧瞧这个  果酱饼干
Check it out! Jam crackers!
好吧  这个人如何
Okay. All right,how's this?
27岁  意大利裔美国人
Twenty-seven, ltalian-American guy.
他是个演员
He's an actor.
在皇后区出生
Born in Queens.
来自大家族  七个姊妹
Wow! Big family. Seven sisters...
他是唯一的...  男孩
...and he's the only... boy.
天啊  个人评价写的是"纽约尼克斯万岁"
Oh,my God! Under personal comments: "New York Knicks rule."
没错  纽约尼克斯万岁
Yeah, the Knicks rule!
乔伊  这个人是你
Joey, this is you!
让我看看
Let me see.
没错
Oh,right!
你什么时候去精子银行了
When did you go to a sperm bank?
就在我参加完纽约大学的性学习之后
Right after I did that sex study down at NYU.
你记不记得你生日时我送你的毛衣
Hey, remember that sweater I gave you for your birthday?
你是用捐精挣的钱买的吗
And that's how you bought it?
不  那是我捐精那天穿的
No. That's what I was wearing when I donated.
我真意外  他们还存着我的小家伙
I'm kinda surprised there's any of my boys left.
宝贝  竞争挺激烈的
Honey, this is pretty competitive.
我这儿还有真正的火箭科学家呢
I mean, I've got actual rocket scientist here.
或许我该打电话过去
Maybe I should call this place
让他们给播一播把我演的连续剧
and get them to put my Days of our Lives gig on here.
让我的小兄弟们活跃活跃
You know, juice this puppy up a little.
那个疯子怎么样了
How's the maniac?
他很讨人喜欢  我们接吻了
He's yummy. We did a little kissing.
菲比  你在做什么
Phoebe,what are you doing?
不  他不会再当跟踪狂了  他为我放弃了
Oh, no, no. You know what, he's not into that anymore. He quit for me.
那家伙迷恋你姐姐  天晓得到底有多久了
This guy has been obsessed with your sister for God knows how long.
一般人不会就这么放弃的
Okay, you don't just give up something like that.
他把他的夜视镜和所有一切都交给我了
He gave me his night-vision goggles and everything.
一个有夜视镜的人说的话你也敢信
You're taking the word of a guy who has night-vision goggles?
他不会再跟踪她了  你觉得他还会跟踪她吗
What, he's not still following her. You think he's still following her?
菲比  快醒醒  限制令可是很严重的事
Phoebe, wake up and smell the restraining order.
你说我该怎么办
What do you say I should do?
若你真的很喜欢他  应该相信他才是
I think if you really like this guy,you should just trust him.
谢谢你  莫妮卡
Thank you, Monica.
或者你该跟踪他  看他去哪里
Or you could follow him, see where he goes.
我也会这么做的  忘了我刚说的吧
That's what I'd do. Forget mine.
天啊  发生什么事
Oh my god. What happened?
钱德勒发神经  把我转了一圈
Oh, god. Crazy Chandler spun me...
然后推下床
...off the bed.
转圈圈啊  听起来很好玩
Wow! Spinning! That sounds like fun.
我倒希望
I wish.
他只是在试验罗斯的那套"拥抱与翻滚"
You know, he was just trying Ross' "hug and roll" thing.
罗斯的什么
Ross' what?
他先抱住你  然后把你滚到一边...
You know when he hugs you and then he rolls you away,and....
我  的  天
Oh... my...God!
-菲比  -是  干嘛
- Phoebe? - Yes, yes.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我只是在找我的...
Oh,I was just here looking for my... my....
吃过的三明治...  在这儿呢
Part of an old sandwich. Here it is!
你在跟踪我吗
Were you following me?
也许
Perhaps.
是的  我很抱歉
Yes. Yes. I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我害怕你仍然迷恋我姐姐
I was just afraid you were still hung up on my sister.
所以你在监视我
So you spied on me.
我真不敢相信你不信任我
I can't believe you don't trust me.
真想不到  我的双胞胎姐姐正好经过
Oh well,what do you know? There goes my identical twin sister!
就这么走过去  跟我长得一模一样
Just walking along, looking like me.
这只是个诡异的巧合
Well, is this a freakish coincidence,
还是你早知道她会搭这班车
or did you know she takes this train?
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我试着罢手  但我做不到
I tried to stop, but I couldn't.
我真可悲
I'm so pathetic.
不  不是你的错  我也有点错
No, no, it's not your fault. No. It's partly my fault.
是我要你决然戒除这个毛病
'cause I made you quit cold turkey.
我不能再跟你约会了  因为你...
Well, I can't date you anymore because you're, you know....
但我一定会帮你忘掉我姐姐
But I will definitely definitely help you get over my sister. Okay?
试着跟踪我一阵子  如何
Stalk me for a while, huh?
我就当个厄休拉的补丁好了
Yeah, and I'll be like an Ursula patch.
我不确定
I don't know.
来吧  瞧  我正在走路
Yeah, just.... Look, I'm going!
来吧
Come on.
我站在柱子边  我会往哪边走呢
I'm on the pillar. Which way will I go?
-你去哪儿 -银行
- Where you going? - To the bank.
精子银行还是普通银行
Sperm or regular?
精子银行
Sperm.
你确定要做这件事
So you're really doing it, huh?
是啊  我挑了一个男的编号37135
Oh, yeah.  I picked a guy. 37135.
听起来不错
Sounds nice.
的确  他有棕发和绿眼睛
I'd say so. He's got brown hair and green eyes.
-不是开玩笑吧  -怎么了
- No kidding? - What?
我以为你会选金发的
I figured you'd have picked a blond guy.
真的吗  为什么
Really? Why?
我不知道  我总是想像
I don't know, I always pictured
你和一个高大聪明的金发男子在一起
you ending up with one of those tall, smart, blond guy
名叫...
named like...
霍伊特
...Hoyt.
Hoyt.
有这名字  没错
It's a name. Yeah.
我看到你们住着一间有宽敞泳池的大别墅里
I saw you in this, you know, this great house with a big pool.
他是游泳选手吗
Is he a swimmer?
他有游泳选手的身材
He's got the body for it.
这我喜欢
I like that.
什么?
What?
你们家里贴着一块标语  上面写着
You guys have one of those signs that says:
"我们不在你家厕所游泳
"We don't swim in your toilet.
你也别在我家池子里尿尿”
So don't pee in our pool."
我们才不会贴那种标语
We are not having one of those signs.
会贴的  因为那会是我送的礼物
Sure you do! It was a gift from me.
你们会生三个很棒的孩子
And you have these three great kids.
-两个女孩和一个男孩  -没错
- Two girls and a boy? - Yeah.
他们戴着小救生圈
And, and they wear those little water wings,
绕着泳池乱跑
and you know they're running around on the deck.
然后霍伊特用大浴巾把他们三个裹在一起
And Hoyt wraps this big towel around all three of them.
是啊
Sure.
但是  你知道这样听起来也不错
But, hey, you know, this way sounds good too.
是啊
Yeah.
莫妮卡
Oh, Monica.
这家伙是宇航员吗
Wow! This guy's an astronaut?
那还真是不错
That would have been cool...
不过也未必
...for like a day.
我打电话给精子银行
I called the sperm bank today.
崔比安尼的小家伙  一点儿也没卖出去
They haven't sold a single unit of Tribbiani.
没有人要我的产品
Nobody wants my product.
我不  我真不明白
I mean, I don't, I don't get it, you know.
我是说
I mean...
可能他们没亲眼见到我
Maybe if they met me in person.
宝贝  你沾到一点...
Honey, you got a little thing on your....
弄掉了吧
Get it?
是啊
Yeah.
好啊
Hello.
好
好吧
Okay.
钱德勒  我可以跟你谈一下吗
Chan, can I talk to you for a second?
当然  什么事
Sure. What's up?
只是补充一点男女关系的想法
Just one additional relationship thought.
这你大概已经很熟悉了
Something you're probably already familiar with.
女人无所不谈
Women talk.